<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Float Geek</title>
		<description>Floating and Software Development</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>What I've been up to lately</title>
				<description>&lt;h2&gt;IoT Fireplace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been asked to share how my IoT fireplace was setup so I decided to turn that knowledge into a blog post. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Summary of why I created this&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to love my gas fireplace.  I don’t have a need for heating the whole house as we spend a lot of our time in the living room.  One issue I was having was the need for getting the living room heated before I come home as I don’t want to heat up rooms I wouldn’t be using.  I decided to take matters into my own hands to make my fireplace connected to the cloud.  It uses a Particle Photon, Relay board, Alexa, and IFTTT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Required Hardware&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.particle.io/collections/photon&quot;&gt;Particle Photon&lt;/a&gt; (make sure to get the one with headers)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/JBtek-Channel-Module-Arduino-Raspberry/dp/B00KTEN3TM/ref=sr_1_3?keywords=single+relay+arduino&amp;amp;qid=1552393042&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;tag=duc0c-20&quot;&gt;Relay Module&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Multicolored-Breadboard-Dupont-Jumper-Wires/dp/B073X7P6N2/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=3HHNG5TDQCIR9&amp;amp;keywords=jumper+wire+arduino&amp;amp;qid=1552393086&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=jumper+wire+ard%2Caps%2C184&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Jumper wire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sofware&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://build.particle.io/build&quot;&gt;Particle Build&lt;/a&gt; (for developing the software)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; (to hook up to Alexa)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Connor-Knabe/fireplace-iot-particle/blob/master/fireplace.ino&quot;&gt;The Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TwfoPlLxzqA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create an IFTTT account if you don’t already have one )&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Setup your Particle photon using the Particle app (iOS/Android stores). You’ll need to connect to the devices WiFi and enter your WiFi password to get it setup. ) Once it’s connected with your account you’ll need to flash the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Connor-Knabe/fireplace-iot-particle/blob/master/fireplace.ino&quot;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; to this device using Particle’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://build.particle.io/build&quot;&gt;Web IDE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Triggering fireplace on from IFTTT app button&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Setup a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/my_applets&quot;&gt;Applet &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Choose button widget (button press)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select Particle &amp;gt; call a function&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select rlySwitchOn “fireplace”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do the same for fireplace off. You can optionally set it to turn&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set name to Fireplace on for a set amount of time use the function (rlySwitch15, rlySwitch60, etc) for 15, 60, or 120 mins. It will turn off after this set time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Triggering fireplace from Alexa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Setup a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/my_applets&quot;&gt;Applet &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Choose Alexa widget (say a specific phrase)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set the phrase something like turn fireplace on&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select Particle &amp;gt; call a function&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select rlySwitchOn “fireplace”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Setting up the hardware&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Setting up alert when Fireplace turns on (optional)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/maker_webhooks&quot;&gt;webhooks&lt;/a&gt; page and click on documentation to get the proper link to use for these triggers. You’ll want to replace the event with fireplace-on or fireplace-off. Your link should look something like https://maker.ifttt.com/trigger/fireplace-on/with/key/las1kjsdfja0sdfja0sdff20aaf.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go back to the Particle &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.particle.io/integrations&quot;&gt;integration&lt;/a&gt; page and select new integration put in the URL from above. Type should be POST, format will be Web Form, Device Any and event name fireplace-on or fireplace-off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now head back to IFTTT and create a new Applet IF Webhook with event name of fireplace-on then THAT notification (note you will need the IFTTT app on your phone for this to be effective). Send notification from IFTTT app. Then hit create action. It will alert you anytime the fireplace has turned on. Do the same for fireplace-off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to talk or ask about what I’ve been working on drop me a line here: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:&amp;#102;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#107;&amp;#51;&amp;#51;&amp;#43;&amp;#98;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;floatgeek33+if@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/IoT_Fireplace</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/04/IoT_Fireplace</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What I've been up to lately</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite some time since I’ve last posted. I’ve been spending most of my free time working on side projects and the float business. I don’t plan to start posting regularly again but I would like to share some of the projects I’ve been working on over the last few years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Holka-Garage (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Connor-Knabe/holka-garage&quot;&gt;Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was a lot of fun to implement!  It all started with a couple of problems that I was having. One problem that my wife and I both shared was a concern that we left the garage open while at work or overnight.  Another was that my garage door opener signal was very weak and I would have to be in my driveway to even open the garage.  You might be thinking well why not just get a longer antenna but that’d only solve one problem and wouldn’t be nearly as enjoyable,  the same goes for buying a smart garage door opener.  This annoyance led me to creating software/hardware that would allow me to open my garage from any distance from my home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Open via GPS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w_uE6Tte2oI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Open via button&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP_ioBE5NLI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alexa/IFTTT Controlled Fireplace&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to love my gas fireplace.  I don’t have a need for heating the whole house as we spend a lot of our time in the living room.  One issue I was having was the need for getting the living room heated before I come home as I don’t want to heat up rooms I wouldn’t be using.  I decided to take matters into my own hands to make my fireplace connected to the cloud.  It uses a Particle Photon, Relay board, Alexa, and IFTTT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TwfoPlLxzqA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Clarity No Show Alert&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One concern I’ve had when owning a business that is run by a team of people is what happens if someone forgets their shift and has to open in the morning.  To help ease my concern I decided to write a program that would verify a teammate is clocked in so long as there is someone booked for an appointment that morning.  It is written in Node.js using Nightmare.js written on top of our booking software (FloatHelm) it sends text alerts to the managers and teammate who is supposed to be clocked in.  If they still don’t clock in after 10 minutes it will call all of us.  Below are photos of the system working and another one when I was working on the code outside in the warm summer weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img75&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/noShowAlert.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img75&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/noShowAlertOutside.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Helm member automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Clarity Float Spa we like to reward our members who have a strong float practice by allowing them to bring a friend every 10 floats they do.  In the past this was a manual process that our manager would have to do.  It was taking up time each week that could be spent on more creative efforts.  So I created a Nightmare.js automation script that would login to the FloatHelm (booking software we use) check to see if a member has reached 10 floats and then adds a task for the manager to send a gift card to that member. Eventually this will automatically generate the gift card and email it off to that member however we like having this be a more personal process at this time by directly emailing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hue energy usage (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Connor-Knabe/hue-energy-usage&quot;&gt;Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to focus some energy on limiting my electrical usage around my home.  Not only does it add up on our monthly utility bills but there is an environmental cost too.  I decided that tracking as many appliances and switching for energy efficient ones (if the numbers make sense) would be worth my time.  One thing that was extremely difficult to track was what sort of electrical footprint my light bulbs were having.  I have many Philips Hue LED light bulbs already so I wanted to know if I had incandescent bulbs which consume close to 6 times more electricity how much am I saving.  This program the tracks energy usage for these bulbs around our house.  It then reports the total costs and yearly and monthly costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img75&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/heu.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nest energy usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners are one of the most energy hungry appliances in a home or an apartment.  Along the same lines as why I track my light bulb energy usage I wanted to do the same for my AC and Furnace.  I previously had a Honeywell Smart thermostat which was great however it did not have a good API that I could use to pull data from it.  This is what prompted me to purchase a Nest Gen 3 thermostat was because the API and documentation were excellent and would allow me to gather the data I needed to solve this problem.  The program I wrote monitors energy usage and gives me an estimate on how much money will be spent on heating/cooling month to month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img75&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/nestEnergyUsage1.PNG&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img75&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/nestEnergyUsage2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Holka-Proxy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have many different programs and services hosted on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.do.co/c/cf0b0981d05d&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; box.  In order to help keep all of the programs secure using SSL I created a reverse proxy. This program handles incoming external requests and routes them securely over SSL to services running on my Ubuntu server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Clarity-Waiver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Clarity Float Spa in the past we would send out hand written letters to customers after their first float.  This process was difficult to track what letters were written and by whom.  To make this easier I hooked into our waiver’s API (SmartWaiver) using Node.js that then would sync data over to a Google Sheet in order for us to keep track of which letters were written. This allowed us to make the process much easier and required much less manual work to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Coach.me Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://Coach.me&quot;&gt;https://Coach.me&lt;/a&gt; it has helped me accomplish many self improvement goals that I set for myself and ultimately I believe has made myself a better person.  There are many habits that I do daily (like meditation) that I would manually have to click every morning.  I do like to keep track of this in the event I do fall out of a meditation habit.  So instead of removing this habit from the app I wrote a little script using Nightmare.js that logs in every morning and checks off my daily habits automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Simple-bank-helper (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Connor-Knabe/simple-bank-helper&quot;&gt;Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering how much money I was spending month to month based on my current budget that was set up with my bank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simple.com/&quot;&gt;https://simple.com/&lt;/a&gt;.  The way I had my budget setup make it difficult to calculate these numbers unless you went back manually and looked to see month to month what the expenses were in each of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simple.com/features/goals&quot;&gt;goals&lt;/a&gt; I had created for that month’s budget.  One thing you might be wondering is why not use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simple.com/features/expenses&quot;&gt;expenses&lt;/a&gt;?  At the time expenses had not come out yet (they came out a few months after I wrote this program actually). The program was written in Node.js and would help me determine where my money has been spent month to month.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/what_ive_been_up_to_lately/simpleBankHelper.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to talk or ask about what I’ve been working on drop me a line here: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:&amp;#102;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#107;&amp;#51;&amp;#51;&amp;#43;&amp;#98;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;floatgeek33+wibutl@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/What_I've_Been_Up_To_Lately</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/What_I've_Been_Up_To_Lately</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Auto Zen Float Tent</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this idea of an automated float center for some time now.  If you’d like to know more about this see my articles titled &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/02/automated-float-tank-center&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Automated Float Tank Center&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/03/how-to-design-an-automated-float-tank-center&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;How to Design An Automated Float Tank Center&lt;/a&gt;.  Since I’ve started working on building a float center of my own called &lt;a href=&quot;https://clarityfloats.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Clarity Float Spa&lt;/a&gt; my mindset on a fully automated float center has started to shift.  I’ve come to realize that having a human element seems to be crucial to a successful float center.  The post float discussion is extremely important, especially for those floatees who just had a profound life changing experience in the tank.  So instead of going for a fully automated center I’ve started creating hardware and software to make running a float center easier. That being said I still think there is a place for a fully automated float tank center but it is not something I am pursuing at this time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The software and hardware I’m creating is designed to make the process of running a float center much smoother.  Instead of spending time worrying about the tanks you can focus on your customers and that personal interaction.  These systems should be able to monitor the water quality including: ph, hydrogen peroxide, specific gravity, alkalinity, water level, and more. All of this data should be accessible from the internet and can be recorded automatically or manually from a smart phone or computer.  There should be systems in place to also handle the lighting of the room, the float tank speakers (if applicable), and the pumps for filtering the water.  Another system that would be useful could monitor if anything goes wrong: pump failure, water leakage, heater failure, etc.  Keep in mind I do not have all of these systems developed yet but it is a work in progress.  I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zenfloatco.com/?tap_a=5195-1d77bb&amp;amp;tap_s=10751-455ee4&amp;amp;tm_banner=sidebar&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Zen Float Tent&lt;/a&gt; and have created some software and harware around it to test out the automated float tank concept.  If you’d like more info on the Zen Float Tent I have a post about it titled &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/09/thoughts-about-the-zen-float-tent&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Thoughts About the Zen Float Tent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Demos of the software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0fiaWlnwovE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Automated Float Demo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full demo of the automated software.  Shows you how to setup the float by choosing: how long your float is, what color before/after, and which music to bring you out of the float.  You may notice lights flashing near the middle (this typically is a warning to wrap up the shower before the float).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bIeb9WJel68&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Appointment Reminders - Confirm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a program I wrote that uses Twilio and Google Calendar API to send appointment reminders for people who are coming to float. The system is setup by adding a user to Google Calendar and entering their cell phone number under notes (only their for first appointment).  The software will know if it is their first time or not based on the number code in the title (00 or 01) and will only include tips for their first float.  This shows the confirmation message.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vfg2ShZ6_J8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Appointment Reminders - Cancel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows the cancelation message for the appointment reminder program.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YzxXtxAGVcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IoT Intex Pump on/off&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the custom Intex pump setup for the Zen Float Tent.  It can be controlled via the website to turn it on and off.  After each float the pump kicks on for 30-45 minutes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hImYL1xOaCI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IoT Intex Pump Timed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo of how to set a timer for how long the Intex pump should run.  This can be run at anytime not just after a float.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HBL7oUec-AI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hydrogen Peroxide Doser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note this is a prototype/proof of concept.  It simply doses hydrogen peroxide throughout the day or from the website. You can also enter a custom amount in milliliters to dose manually.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8XXIlJKzYy0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hydrogen Peroxide Container&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the container that holds the hydrogen peroxide.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lleIsPFuNII&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Water Sensor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a water sensor that will send a text message and turn off pumps if water is detected.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VkAHd2tJ1xE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GFCI Alert&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program sends a text message alert when the GFCI outlet trips. This is good because most of the equipment (heater, pump, lights) should be hooked up to a GFCI outlet in a float room.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see a bright future for the internet of things in the float community.  I think it will allow more quality customer interaction and less things to have to maintain manually.  At the end of the day it is the customers who really matter and taking some of the work away from the tanks and dedicating that time to more positive customer interactions seems to make sense.  I think software like this will make float centers even more of an enjoyable place to work and be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to talk about this further drop me a line here: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:&amp;#102;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#107;&amp;#51;&amp;#51;&amp;#43;&amp;#98;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;floatgeek33@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/Auto_Zen_Float_Tent</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/06/Auto_Zen_Float_Tent</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Favorite Companies of 2015</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;This is a list of my favorite companies from 2015 that I really appreciate.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zenfloatco.com?tap_a=5195-1d77bb&amp;amp;tap_s=10751-455ee4&amp;amp;tm_banner=sidebar&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo logo2&quot; src=&quot;https://static.tapfiliate.com/56391821ec220.png?a=5195-1d77bb&amp;amp;s=10751-455ee4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
    Zen Float Company is the amazing company that created the Zen Float Tent.  They raised $295,000 on
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1070936311/zen-float-tent-first-affordable-isolation-tank-for&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; to get production going for their first version of the tent.  The Zen Float Tent has been an extremely useful tool for myself and my roommates for relaxation, recovery from workouts, introspection, clarity, etc. The best part about having one of these is that we can float anytime in the comfort of our own home. I like this company so much that I’ve even started sponsoring them.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: clicking the image above will take you to their site and I get a portion of the sale :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.org/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo logo2&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/Raspberry_Pi_Logo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
    The Raspberry Pi Foundation is the awesome company that created the Raspberry Pi.  If you haven’t heard of a Raspberry Pi it is basically a small computer about the size of a credit card.  It costs less than $50 and you can interface with all sorts of sensors (motion, temperature, etc).  Recently they released the Pi Zero which is a $5 version of the Pi.  This is going to make it very easy for anyone even with a small budget to learn about software development and servers.  I’m so grateful for this company for opening the doors to the masses to get involved in cool projects without spending a fortune on hardware.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo logo2&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/trello.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trello is an amazing software tool that can help you utilize &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;kanban&lt;/a&gt; which is a scheduling system for lean production.  This can be applied to software development, home improvement projects, starting a business, etc.  I’ve been using Trello for over a year now and it has been extremely useful especially for side coding projects I work on.  If you are a person who loves todo lists and checking things off Trello would be worth a shot.  It can really help you stay on top of your work and collaborate with others on projects.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo logo2&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/slack.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
    Slack is a communication tool which is designed for businesses and other organizations which can replace email.  I started using slack Summer of 2014 and it really made me see how communication could be done differently.  The value of having more real time communication seems to cut back drastically on how long it takes to get to the point of a conversation. Also the formality of email seems to go out the window when using Slack.  It also seems to encourage group conversations better than emails.  These are just a few of the many reasons why you should consider using Slack over email.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twilio.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo logo2&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/twilio.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
    Twilio is a developers best friend if they need to send affordable text messages or voice calls over the internet.  Twilio is an API used by developers at companies including: Uber, Box, Intuit, Hulu, Ebay, and more!  Twilio is also used for two-factor authentication, appointment reminders, sales leads, and more.  If you’re ever needing to send out texts or do any sort of communication involving software and phones I would highly recommend choosing Twilio.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m very passionate about companies doing the right thing and that are making the world a better place.  If you have any favorite companies that you really love leave a comment below :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/Favorite_Companies_of_2015</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/02/Favorite_Companies_of_2015</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Float Geeks Podcast</title>
				<description>&lt;h2&gt;Float Geeks Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://floatgeeks.io&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/floatgeeks/floatgeeks_logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently a friend and myself have started a podcast. It’s called Float Geeks which is a podcast all about floating.  The whole idea is to interview and chat with people across the industry and really dive deep into why float tanks are so awesome.  We touch on how to hack float tanks, what happens inside the tank, research around floating, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see all of the episodes on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://floatgeeks.io&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;https://floatgeeks.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also we are on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/float-geeks/id1058855632?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/float-geeks&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the first episode to give you a taste of what to expect in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:450px;height:180px;border:0;overflow:hidden;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;https://app.stitcher.com/splayer/f/77331/42274195?el=0&amp;amp;refid=stpr&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/11/FloatGeeks_Podcast</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/11/FloatGeeks_Podcast</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Custom Filtration System For The Zen Float tent</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7073.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Pump view&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7073.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently written a blog post about my initial thoughts of the Zen Float Tent &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/09/Thoughts_About_the_Zen_Float_Tent&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Like I have mentioned in this post I setup a custom filtration system to support the pump that came with the tent.  This post is dedicated to help you setup your own custom filtration system for the Zen Float Tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Parts list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of the parts needed for this tutorial please fill out the form below (which will allow you to sign up for the newsletter and receive the parts document)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/slim-081711.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
    #mc_embed_signup1{ clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; }
	/* Add your own MailChimp form style overrides in your site stylesheet or in this style block.
	   We recommend moving this block and the preceding CSS link to the HEAD of your HTML file. */
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;//floatgeek.us11.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=23d4e2d4dc565ca74304ccf58&amp;amp;id=3fe45437f2&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; name=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; class=&quot;validate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup_scroll&quot;&gt;
	&lt;label for=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot;&gt;Subscribe to our mailing list&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;EMAIL&quot; class=&quot;email&quot; id=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot; placeholder=&quot;email address&quot; required=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;b_23d4e2d4dc565ca74304ccf58_3fe45437f2&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; value=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Subscribe&quot; name=&quot;subscribe&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7046.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Tube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7046.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7059.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Parts&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7059.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7060.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Rubber insert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7060.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7062.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Size Converter&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7062.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7063.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Tube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7063.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7064.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Cutting PVC&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7064.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7066.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Connecting PVC&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7066.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7067.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Connecting PVC #2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7067.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7068.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Angle of pipe view&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7068.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7071.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Hooking it into tent&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7071.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7072.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Finishing touches&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/rsz_IMG_7072.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Click photo to enlarge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Type of filter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this specific setup I used an Intex pump which can be purchased from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005QIYM6E?keywords=intex&amp;amp;qid=1446321354&amp;amp;ref_=sr_ph&amp;amp;sr=1&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Setting the piping up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these parts can be purchased from Lowe’s for under $100 (not including the pump).  Once you have all of the parts it is best to start with the tubing that came with the Intex pump and hook in the adapter which will screw on snugly (Image 3-4). You will need a rubber grommet to seal the gap between the adapter and the Intex tube(Image 3).  This will prevent the water from leaking out.  Once that connection is secure you can figure out where you would like your tubes to enter the tent.  For my setup I had the PVC tubes enter the tent from the back close to the pump that came with the tent.  This makes it easy to access since it is near a corner of the tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to calculate how long you would like the PVC tubes to be in order to go inside of the tent and what angles you would like.  Depending on how you want the tubes to enter the tent and if you are using a spill berm or not this may vary.  I would recommend using a tape measure before you start cutting to get a sense of how long the tubes will need to be.  The images above will give you a good idea of how I decided to get my PVC piping into the tent and notice the multiple angles (to prevent light leaks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7068.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery2&quot; title=&quot;Angled pipe&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/custom_filter/IMG_7068.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keep in mind that you may want to put a small angle in the tube that pumps the water back into the tent (see image above). This will make the water ripple which can help prevent biofilm from building up on the surface of the water.  Also make sure that your intake tube is not touching the tents bottom and also submerged under water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have laid out how long you want the PVC pipes to be you can use the PVC primer and glue to glue the pieces together (careful not to inhale or touch the glue/primer).&lt;br /&gt;
It might be useful to put the Intex pump inside of a rubber container to help catch salt water in the event that some leaks when changing the filter (highly recommended).  Then make sure that the PVC pipes are in place and hook the hose into the pump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This specific pump requires you to prime it before using. There are more instructions in the Intex manual about this, but essentially you need to make sure the pump is filled with water before you start it for the first time.  Also you will need to open the air valve on the top while filling it until some water leaks out.  Once the water leaks out screw the air valve tight and turn the pump on.  If it doesn’t start pumping water you may have to open the air valve when it is running (note water may splash, use a towel to open air valve).  Once you hear the pump working and see water moving through it you can close the air value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You should be all set!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck customizing your Zen Float Tent!  Leave comments below if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/Custom_Filtration_System_For_The_Zen_Float_tent</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/Custom_Filtration_System_For_The_Zen_Float_tent</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Thoughts About the Zen Float Tent</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/zft.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery0&quot; title=&quot;Zen Float Tent&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/zft.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/zft.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;ZFT&quot; data-title=&quot;My caption&quot;&gt;Zen Float Tent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The journey to getting a Zen Float Tent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently purchased a Zen Float Tent.  Like I have mentioned in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/Why_I_Chose_The_Zen_Float_Tent/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; there has been much contemplation about getting this tent.  When I first heard about the Kickstarter I was a bit skeptical of the quality and design of the tent.  I was familiar with the Samadhi Tank, Escape Pod, various pods and rooms all of which are of high build quality.  I decided that I was going to wait until the tent had been used and reviewed before I would purchase one.  This Summer I decided that the Zen Float Tent was right for me and when I was on a drive from Florida to St. Louis while looking on Facebook I noticed a post from Jeremy at &lt;a href=&quot;https://escapepodtank.com&quot;&gt;Escape Pod Tank&lt;/a&gt; saying he had one for sale.  Naturally this was the perfect opportunity so I ended up purchasing the tent from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installation of the Zen Float Tent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly the Zen Float Tent was not terribly difficult to setup.  My situation was a bit unique because I custom build a base and a filtration system for the tent but overall it took about a weekend to get it all up and running. There are some great YouTube videos online that show you how to set it up and the instruction manual was informative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6809.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Boards&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6809.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6831.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Cutting plywood&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6831.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6838.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Rubber soundproofing&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6838.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6842.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Spill berm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6842.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6961.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Getting reverse osmosis water from store&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6961.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6983.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Filling with water&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6983.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6877.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Full of water&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6877.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6942.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Filling with salt&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_6942.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_7068.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Custom PVC&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_7068.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_7071.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Custom pipe&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_7071.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_7073.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Pool pump&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_7073.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_7008.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;gallery1&quot; title=&quot;Complete tent&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/rsz_IMG_7008.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Click photo to enlarge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video class=&quot;vid50&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; id=&quot;Vid3&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6833.mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Platform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process started with the base which consisted of six 12”x2” pieces of wood from Lowe’s.  This would help with absorbing some sound and distribute the weight across the floor.  On top of the wood platform there is a thin piece of plywood to make a smooth surface.  On top of the plywood are three 6’x4’ pieces of sound absorbing rubber purchased from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acousticalsurfaces.com/acoust_flooring/nuetra_phone.htm&quot;&gt;Acoustical Surfaces&lt;/a&gt;.  This is to ensure that the tent is completely soundproof especially from vibrations traveling through the floor.  The main sounds that seem to travel into the tank are vibrational such as door slams and people walking. When the base was complete it covered 12 feet by 6 feet which fits perfectly in the room (even allowing space for a yoga mat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video class=&quot;vid50&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; id=&quot;Vid1&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6840.mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Spill Berm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the spill berm was setup on top of this platform.  The spill berm was designed for industrial spills including harmful chemical spills.  This seemed to be the perfect device to catch any excess water or if the tent leaked.  I had a white (epsom salt is harder to see on white) custom made spill berm that was 11’x5’ that will ensure plenty of space for the 8’x4’ tent.  Also having this much space allowed me to make the tent go across the wood beams diagonally to keep the weight distributed across multiple beams (5-6 beams instead of 4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the berm was setup it was time to install the tent which you can see the process in the photos above.  This was a fairly easy process which consisted of placing metal rods into the vinyl and then connecting the pieces.  After all the rods were in place I started filling the tent with reverse osmosis water.  You might wonder why I filled the tent with reverse osmosis water and not just tap water.  I did this because there can be some heavy metals such as iron in the water supply and also chlorine and other chemicals which I don’t want in the tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video class=&quot;vid50&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; id=&quot;Vid2&quot; src=&quot;/images/Thoughts_About_ZFT/IMG_6953.mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Epsom Salt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally it was time for the Epsom salt which I purchased from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfsalt.com/epsom-salt-for-floatation-tanks&quot;&gt;Sf Salt Co&lt;/a&gt;. They have really good prices on bulk Epsom salt and they also were at the &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/Highlights_From_the_2015_Float_Conference&quot;&gt;Float Conference&lt;/a&gt; this year.  I ended up purchasing 1,100 lbs from them which arrived on a pallet in individual 50lb bags.  As of this blog post I have around 635lbs of Epsom salt and about 115 gallons of water in the tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Custom Filtration System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also decided to make a custom filtration system that would supplement the tent’s standard filter system.  I purchased an Intex pool pump from Amazon and bought some PVC piping that would fit into the Intex system.  When it was all said and done the pump worked great and is run for 30+ minutes after each float.  This is to help ensure the water stays clean and can help speed up the time it takes to heat up the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely satisfied with the Zen Float Tent thus far.  I would recommend it to anyone looking to buy a float tank for their home.  The material quality is top notch and it does a pretty good job of light proofing. Also I would recommend purchasing 35% hydrogen peroxide and a shammy to wipe down the tent before getting into it.  The base I made is not a necessity but it seems to make sense especially if you are not putting this in a basement of a quiet home.  If you have any questions please leave a comment below.  Also there is a form now to sign up for the newsletter, check it out!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/Thoughts_About_the_Zen_Float_Tent</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/Thoughts_About_the_Zen_Float_Tent</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Highlights From the 2015 Float Conference</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://floatconference.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/floatcon.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is the Float Conference?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Float Conference took place last weekend in Portland Oregon.  This event is a conference where people interested in float tanks go including: researchers, float tank manufactures, salt companies, float center employees/owners, float enthusiasts, NSF employees, health department regulators, and more. The conference is a place for everyone in the industry to get together and to have meaningful discussions about the direction we want the floating industry to move.  Also the conference has been a place for researchers to discuss their past research on the benefits of floating and Justin Feinstein and his team from LIBR (Loretta Institute for Brain Research) have recently started sharing their findings of their new research.  We are in exciting times for the float industry as more and more tank manufactures pop up, new float centers open every year, and more people know about floating than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Important talks at the conference:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to pick out certain talks that will be mentioned here because every talk at the conference was really phenomenal and informative.  Ashkahn from &lt;a href=&quot;https://floathq.com&quot;&gt;Float On&lt;/a&gt; really has done a great job getting these speakers together and lined up.  The amount of hours put into this conference was tremendous and Ashkahn showed that himself alone spent over 1,000 hours working on the conference and in total it was closer to 2,000 for everyone involved.  I cannot say thank you enough to the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://floathq.com&quot;&gt;Float On&lt;/a&gt; for organizaing this conference because without them it would not have been possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laureateinstitute.org/justin-feinstein.html&quot;&gt;LIBR&lt;/a&gt; research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6631.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15a&quot; title=&quot;Loretta Institute for Brain Research&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6631.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(This study was referenced in a talk by Justin Feinstein.  Those who have floated clearly know this is not the case in the tank)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One speaker that really stood out was the neuropsychologist Justin Feinstein.  The work he and his team are doing at LIBR is truly amazing, they are taking fMRI images of the brain before and after 3 floats to see how it changes with these floats.  They are doing RCTs (randomized controlled studies) in order to validate that their findings are scientifically accurate. Currently the research is preliminary but we will soon have research that has solid conclusions on how floating can change the brain.  He and his team want to study the effects of floating on PTSD, addictions, anxiety, and eating disorders such as anorexia.  I won’t go over specifically what the results were from the fMRI scans but his team is very fascinated in interoception (being aware of your physical sensations such as heart beat or breath) and it seems like the float tank can enhance this, based on my own experience.  This is interesting because in Vipassana meditation there is a heavy emphasis on focusing on physical sensations such as feeling hot, cold, tingling, numbness, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Emily Noren&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great talk was by Emily Noren, a young woman that had anorexia, who discovered floating about a year ago in search to help with this disease. Emily got on the stage, with such an open heart, started talking about her battle with anorexia from a young teenager until an adult.  She had a great analogy about how this voice in her head she called “Ed” would aggravate her eating disorder and make her think about counting calories, weight, body image etc.  She started using the tank because a friend of hers, Sandra Calm, was a co-owner of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://floatshoppe.com&quot;&gt;Float Shoppe&lt;/a&gt; and suggested she give floating a shot.  She started floating and it wasn’t easy at first but she made an effort to keep coming back and with time this voice “Ed” started fading away. A new voice took place of “Ed” which stopped caring about the calories and what she ate.  After floating for about a year she has seen a noticeable diminish in the eating disorder.  Her speech was so touching it brought me to tears and her talk was met by a standing ovation at the end.  She has written a book called &lt;i&gt;Unsinkable&lt;/i&gt; about it which she has posted on her website (for free) at &lt;a href=&quot;https://emilykatenoren.com&quot;&gt; emilykatenoren.com&lt;/a&gt; and can also be purchased on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Unsinkable-discovering-recovering-addiction-depression/dp/151471051X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1440121598&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=unsinkable+float+book&quot;&gt; Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Entreprenuer talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6633.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15&quot; title=&quot;Entreprenuer talk&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6633.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6634.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15&quot; title=&quot;Entreprenuer talk&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6634.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6636.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15&quot; title=&quot;Entreprenuer talk&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6636.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6637.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15&quot; title=&quot;Entreprenuer Talk&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6637.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There was a great talk by Nick from &lt;a href=&quot;https://truerest.com/&quot;&gt;True REST&lt;/a&gt; and Andy from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.floathouse.ca/&quot;&gt;Float House&lt;/a&gt; which are two large franchises the former started in Arizona and the latter Canada.  They were explaining how float centers shouldn’t devalue the floats by continuously offering discounts like Groupon, Social Shopper, and Living Social.  They were explaining how the industry is taking off and float centers are popping up rapidly.  For example in 2009 in the USA there were around 15-20 float centers with 3+ tanks and in Canada there was just 1 center.  In 2015 there are now 271 active float centers in the USA and in Canada there are 56 active float centers.  Floating seems to be spreading faster than ever and I don’t see it slowing down anytime soon.  Especially based on the fact that there were about 500 people at the conference this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Glenn and Lee Perry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6643.JPG&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15c&quot; title=&quot;Glenn and Lee Perry&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6643.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and Lee Perry were at this years conference again.  Glenn and Lee were two of the first residential float tank manufactures back in the 1970s with John Lilly creating the first tank outside of the research labs. They have a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://samadhitank.com/&quot;&gt;Samadhi Tank Co&lt;/a&gt; where they sell durable float tanks some of which have lasted over 25 years.  Their talk was mostly focused on why float centers should start selling float tanks.  The reason behind this is that not everyone who wants to float will want to do it in a public place.  As always the Perry’s talk was very inspirational and you can really see how much passion they have to keep this industry moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Float On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6652.JPG&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15d&quot; title=&quot;Grham and Ashkahn&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6652.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Graham and Ashkahn from &lt;a href=&quot;https://floathq.com&quot;&gt;Float On&lt;/a&gt; always seem to have an incredibly energetic talk that seems to keep everyone engaged.  This year they talked about how the Washington monument took over 100 years to be built and how there was a lot of planning involved instead of work actually being done.  I think the purpose of this talk was to really inspire future float tank manufactures and center founders to stop worrying and planning and start doing.  Kind of like the saying goes “one in the hand two in the bush”.  You can always correct mistakes later on and it is impossible to predict everything that will go wrong, especially with a float center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kevin Johnson from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zerogravityinstitute.com/&quot;&gt;Zero Gravity Institue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6655.JPG&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15e&quot; title=&quot;Kevin Johnson&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6655.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kevin Johnson had an amazing talk last year about how to market your float business to early adopters.  This year’s talk by him also was outstanding.  He first explained how Zero Gravity Institute is going to partner up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://onnit.com&quot;&gt;Onnit&lt;/a&gt; to create even better float rooms.  He then talked about how as an industry we need to band together and cooperate with one another.  This was really refreshing as the industry is getting larger we are starting to see more people getting into the industry for various motivations.  Kevin also explained how he would be happy to help any float tank center who is planning on opening for free.  This is really great to hear especially because he is setting an example for other float centers to help one another out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Crash from Float Labs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6664.JPG&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;FloatCon15f&quot; title=&quot;Crash&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img50&quot; src=&quot;/images/2015conference/rsz_IMG_6664.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last but not least Crash from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefloatlab.com&quot;&gt;Float Labs&lt;/a&gt; spoke this year about why we need to protect our industry with getting our float tanks NSF certified.  Last year was a bit controversial because some people misunderstood and thought that because he initiated the NSF standard for float tanks that he was trying to flush out competition by getting expensive tests done.  I’ve come to think this is not the case but instead he just wants this industry to be safe and to not have to worry about health departments shutting down float tank centers from the lack of NSF certifications.  Crash really seems to care about this industry and doesn’t care what other people think of him especially if he is doing what he thinks is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both years I’ve been the float conference have been amazing experiences.  I would recommend this conference for anyone who likes floating or the float culture.  I plan on going back next year August 20th-21st 2016 and would love to see more people out there (leave a comment below if you are going to attend)! Every year it seems like more and more people attend and it’s really great to see the same people each year.  There is really something special about this industry that revolves around a sense of community and good will for others.  More info can be found on the float conference’s website  &lt;a href=&quot;https://floatconference.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/08/Highlights_From_the_2015_Float_Conference</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/08/Highlights_From_the_2015_Float_Conference</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why I Chose The Zen Float Tent</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After about a year and a half of consideration I’ve finally decided to purchase a Zen Float Tent.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenfloatco.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_zenfloattent.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of getting a float tank has been bouncing around in my mind for a couple of years now.  I had thought about the Escape Pod Tank or the Samadhi Tank but just couldn’t justify the cost of those for residential use.  These tanks are great, however paying $6,000+ for a tank just didn’t seem to be feasible for something that wouldn’t be used for commercial purposes.  The Zen Float Tent comes in just under $2,000 which is a lot more affordable especially considering that the cost of salt could run you close to $600 to fill it up initially (plus more for maintenance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three reasons why to choose the Zen Float Tent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Affordable&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Light weight&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Aesthetically Pleasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to purchase a higher end float tank for my home (or even a float center) the Escape Pod Tank is on the top of the list.  They are very durable (stainless steel) and the filtration system seems to be very robust.  Also their pricing is very reasonable at under $10,000 for a commercial grade tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what the Escape Pod looks like (2015 model).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://escapepodtank.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/ywoNiObl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically with a commercial grade tank they have higher end filters that clean the water much more quickly than in a residential tank.  In the case of my setup I will have another filtration system besides the standard one that comes with the Zen Float Tent.  The reason being is that I know many people who are interested in floating and want to make sure the water is very pure for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Custom filtration system:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible additional filter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Intex-1500-Gallon-Filter-Pump-120-Volt/dp/B005QIYM6E/ref=sr_1_1?srs=2594064011&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1431293710&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Intex+1500+Pool+filter+pump&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_filter.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this tank I plan on using 35% hydrogen peroxide to help sanitize the water. H202 + UV has been studied as an effective way to clean/disinfect the water. See the EPA post about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://iaspub.epa.gov/tdb/pages/treatment/treatmentOverview.do?treatmentProcessId=-300168699&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;here.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; There also have been many studies done on the combination of UV + H202 in disinfecting water which can be found on&lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?start=10&amp;amp;q=h202+and+uv+sanitizing+water&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,26&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Google Scholar.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
If your really interested in how this works UV + H202 forms &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydroxyl_radical&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;hydroxyl radicals&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;which are often referred to as the “detergents” of the atmosphere because they react with many pollutants, often acting as the first step to their removal.  This makes sense that UV + H202 can disinfect water effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically H202 comes in 3% solutions but for the sake of sanitization 35% makes more sense economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Certified-Hydrogen-Peroxide-Dropper-Bottle/dp/B00J0DAAVW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1436357494&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=hydrogen+peroxide+35&amp;amp;pebp=1436357532762&amp;amp;perid=1FWDJS2RPAWBGKVQR61H&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_h202b.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zen Float Tent comes with one filter pump which includes a UV light (note: the new upgraded tent v1.5 includes two pumps). Just to make sure that the water is ultra pure I may end up getting another UV light to attach to the intex pool pump just to have more of those hydroxyl radicals that I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pondmaster-02910-Violet-Clarifier-10watt/dp/B00025YVGW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1436358117&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=ultraviolet+light+pond &quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_uvlight.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Isolating sound&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound isolation is a typical problem with float tanks especially low frequency sounds such as people walking or cars driving by.  These sounds can travel well throughs solid objects such as the walls and the water that you will be floating in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this issue I plan on purchasing a neoprene rubber anti-vibration pad to help absorb these sounds if they are too distracting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shop-Fox-W1322-Anti-Vibration-24-Inch/dp/B000OQTV2I/ref=sr_1_1/191-8040367-2256009?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1431379730&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=neoprene+sheet&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/vibrationPad.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally there is the issue of the tank leaking if some sharp object gets into the tank and tears the vinyl.  For this I plan on purchasing an industrial spill berm to catch water if the tent leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aireindustrial.net/spill-berms/spill-containment-berm.asp&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/spillberm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/Why_I_Chose_The_Zen_Float_Tent</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/Why_I_Chose_The_Zen_Float_Tent</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>3 Parts of An Automated Float Tank Center</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The reason for this post is to speak in more detail about what will be required to create a fully automated float center. Some of the components that will need to be implemented will include Arduinos(microcontrollers), access cards(to get into building), a database(storing user info), Stripe/Paypal(credit card processor), and networking to tie the whole system into the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Various components to the system&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will break down the whole system into 3 different systems. These systems are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scheduling/Billing System&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Building security&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Filtration/clean up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Scheduling/Billing System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the system that will be designed around a website that will allow floaters to sign up on the website and schedule floats.&lt;br /&gt;
There are already many versions of this type of software developed however one needs to be custom designed to fit in with the automated float center. Some examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://floathelm.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;FloatHelm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontdeskhq.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;FrontDesk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenplanner.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;ZenPlanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindbodyonline.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;MindBodyOnline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scheduling all starts with the customer wanting to book at float online.  He will go to the website and there will be a button that will pull up the scheduling application.  From there they can pick the time they want to float and then pay using a credit card.  This system will need to be tied into the building security system which will permit the user to gain access using their access card or PIN number when they show up to float.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;User books/pays for float online&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Access card is activated for the time they have scheduled&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They show up and their access card allows them to enter their specified float room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Building security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain security for the building and the customers who use this facility there must be strict access into the building only permitted if that user has scheduled a float.
The reason for strict access is that we only want floaters who are permitted into the facility at their designated float time,  if this is not the case then people may be tempted to steal floats or to disrupt the peaceful waiting room which could become overcrowded.  The access control software would be able to keep track of how long users stay at the float tank center including time during, before, and after their float.  These metrics would be a lot easier to obtain if the only permitted people into the building have been authorized to float.  These metrics could be used to help cut back on unnecessary time spent between float sessions and to help provide an overall better experience for the floater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This aspect of the float center would operate similar to a 24/7 tanning salon except that users only have a certain time window in which they can gain access to the facility.  This system would need an access card reader or PIN pad on the front door and on each of the float tank room doors.  When the user arrives they will already know which room they are floating in via text message or email, so they can go into the facility and head to the room they have booked for floating.  Once the user enters their room they will take a shower and then enter the tank.  A sensor will be placed on the door of the room which will detect when it was opened and will know to start a timer which will play music in the tank when the float time is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain problems can appear at this stage of the process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What if the floater arrives late for their float?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;How do you prevent a floater from staying longer in the tank?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What if the floater has health complications in the tank?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat some of these problems there will need to be fail-safes in place.  Let’s take the example of the floater arriving late for their appointment.  If the floater arrives more than 15 minutes late the front door would not allow them to enter.  This would keep the process moving smoothly because if a floater arrives late it could push back the floats for other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that a floater stays in the tank longer than scheduled, there will be various ways to “encourage” them to get out of the tank. When the time is up there first might be some music that begins to play in their float tank.  Then if they still have not gotten out (motion sensor to detect this) a light could come on and then start flashing if they continue to stay in the tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third problem is a bit tricky because without someone being on site it might be hard to know if someone is having problems in the tank.  This issue could be compared to a swimming pool that has no lifeguard on duty where there would be a disclaimer that in the event something bad happens there may be no one to help you.  Besides this disclaimer another useful option would be to place an “emergency” button inside the tank so if the floater is having issues they can hit the button and it will dial 911 and they could talk to them via a speaker in the tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Filtration/clean up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between float sessions it is necessary to run the tank’s filtration system in order to clean all of the water of bad bacteria and pathogens that may have accumulated after a person’s float.  This system will be implemented by using a motion detector to sense when a person has gotten out of the tank and has started their post float shower.  Something to keep in mind the system would have to verify that that floater’s time has been used up in the event that they were planning on going back to continue floating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically the floater will use a towel, ear plugs, and maybe Q-tips which they will need to dispose of after their float is over.  For this type of float center there would be a trash can and a laundry basket in order to keep the room clean.  Also it is critical that there is a large stack of towels laid out so that the every floater will have fresh towels throughout the day.  At the end of the day there will need to be a person who comes in an does laundry and takes out the trash.  There could be an incentive where a floater gets one float at half price if they do some chores around the center and help clean up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum things up there are a lot of technical aspects that go into creating an automated float tank center.  Clearly this system needs to be well thought out ahead of time and designed carefully with fail-safes in place to help deal with any problems that might occur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2015/03/How_To_Design_An_Automated_Float_Tank_Center</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/03/How_To_Design_An_Automated_Float_Tank_Center</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
