<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Float Geek</title>
		<description>Floating and Software Development</description>
		<link>http://floatgeek.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://floatgeek.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Highlights From the 2015 Float Conference</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://floatconference.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/floatcon.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is the Float Conference?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Float Conference took place last weekend in Portland Oregon.  This event is a conference where people interested in float tanks go including: researchers, float tank manufactures, salt companies, float center employees/owners, float enthusiasts, NSF employees, health department regulators, and more. The conference is a place for everyone in the industry to get together and to have meaningful discussions about the direction we want the floating industry to move.  Also the conference has been a place for researchers to discuss their past research on the benefits of floating and Justin Feinstein and his team from LIBR (Loretta Institute for Brain Research) have recently started sharing their findings of their new research.  We are in exciting times for the float industry as more and more tank manufactures pop up, new float centers open every year, and more people know about floating than ever before.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Important talks at the conference:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s difficult to pick out certain talks that will be mentioned here because every talk at the conference was really phenomenal and informative.  Ashkahn from Float On (floathq.com) really has done a great job getting these speakers together and lined up.  The amount of hours put into this conference was tremendous and Ashkahn showed that himself alone spent over 1,000 hours working on the conference and in total it was closer to 2,000 for everyone involved.  I cannot say thank you enough to the team at Float On for organizaing this conference because without them it would not have been possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;LIBR research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laureateinstitute.org/justin-feinstein.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6631.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(This study was referenced in a talk by Justin Feinstein.  Those who have floated clearly know this is not the case in the tank)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One speaker that really stood out was of course Justin Feinstein.  The work he and his team are doing at LIBR is truly amazing, they are taking fMRI images of the brain before and after 3 floats to see how it changes with these floats.  They are doing RCTs (randomized controlled studies) in order to validate that their findings are scientifically accurate. Currently the research is preliminary but we will soon have research that has solid conclusions on how floating can change the brain.  He and his team want to study the effects of floating on PTSD, addictions, anxiety, and eating disorders such as anorexia.  I won&amp;#39;t go over specifically what the results were from the fMRI scans but his team is very fascinated in interception (being aware of your physical sensations such as heart beat or breath) it seems like the float tank can enhance this based on my own experience.  This is interesting because in Vipassana meditation there is a heavy emphasis on focusing on physical sensations such as feeling hot, cold, tingling, numbness, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Emily Noren&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great talk was by Emily Noren, a young woman that had anorexia, who discovered floating about a year ago in search to help with this disease. Emily got on the stage, with such an open heart, started talking about her battle with anorexia from a young teenager until an adult.  She had a great analogy about how this voice in her head she called &amp;quot;Ed&amp;quot; would aggravate her eating disorder and make her think about counting calories, weight, body image etc.  She started using the tank because a friend of hers, Sandra Calm, was a co-owner of the Float Shoppe (floatshoppe.com) and suggested she give floating a shot.  She started floating and it wasn&amp;#39;t easy at first but she made an effort to keep coming back and with time this voice &amp;quot;Ed&amp;quot; started fading away. A new voice took place of &amp;quot;Ed&amp;quot; which stopped caring about the calories and what she ate.  After floating for about a year she has seen a noticeable diminish in the eating disorder.  Her speech was so touching it brought me to tears and her talk was met by a standing ovation at the end.  She has written a book called &lt;i&gt;Unsinkable&lt;/i&gt; about it which she has posted on her website (for free) (emilykatenoren.com) and can also be purchased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Entreprenuer talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6633.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6634.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6636.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6637.jpg&quot; /&gt;
There was a great talk by Nick from &lt;a href=&quot;http://truerest.com/&quot;&gt;True REST&lt;/a&gt; and Andy from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.floathouse.ca/&quot;&gt;Float House&lt;/a&gt; which are two large franchises one started in Arizona and the other Canada.  They were explaining how float centers shouldn&amp;#39;t devalue the floats by continuously offering discounts like Groupon, Social Shopper, and Living Social.  They were explaining how the industry is taking off and float centers are popping up rapidly.  For example in 2009 in the USA there were around 15-20 float centers with 3+ tanks and in Canada there was just 1 center.  In 2015 there are now 271 active float centers in the USA and in Canada there are 56 active float centers.  Floating seems to be spreading faster than ever and I don&amp;#39;t see it slowing down anytime soon.  Especially based on the fact that there were about 500 people at the conference this year.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Glenn and Lee Perry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samadhitank.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6643.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Glenn and Lee Perry were at this years conference again.  Glenn and Lee were two of the first residential float tank manufactures back in the 70s with John Lilly creating the first tank outside of the research labs. They have a company called Samadhi tank co where they sell durable float tanks some of which have lasted over 25 years.  Their talk was mostly focused on why float centers should start selling float tanks.  The reason behind this is that not everyone who wants to float will want to do it in a public place.  As always the Perry&amp;#39;s talk was very inspirational and you can really see how much passion they have to keep this industry moving forward.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Float On&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://floathq.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6652.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Graham and Ashkahn from Float on (floathq.com) always seem to have an incredibly energetic talk that seems to keep everyone engaged.  This year they talked about how the Washington monument took over 100 years to be built and how there was a lot of planning involved instead of work actually being done.  I think the purpose of this talk was to really inspire future float tank manufactures and center founders to stop worrying and planning and start doing.  Kind of like the saying goes &amp;quot;one in the hand two in the bush&amp;quot; you can always correct later if mistakes are made and you cannot predict everything that will go wrong especially with a float center.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kevin Johnson from Zero Gravity Institue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zerogravityinstitute.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6655.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Kevin Johnson had an amazing talk last year about how to market your float business to early adopters.  This year&amp;#39;s talk by him also was outstanding.  He first explained how Zero Gravity Institute is going to partner up with Onnit (onnit.com) to create even better float rooms.  He then talked about how as an industry we need to band together and cooperate with one another.  This was really refreshing as the industry is getting larger we are starting to see more people getting into the industry for various motivations.  Kevin also explained how he would be happy to help any float tank center who is planning on opening for free.  This is really great to hear especially because he is setting an example for other float centers to help one another out.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Crash from Float Labs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thefloatlab.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015conference/IMG_6664.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Last but not least Crash spoke this year about why we need to protect our industry with getting our float tanks NSF certified.  Last year was a bit controversial because some people misunderstood and thought that because he initiated the NSF standard for float tanks that he was trying to flush out competition by getting expensive tests done.  I&amp;#39;ve come to think this is not the case but instead he just wants this industry to be safe and to not have to worry about health departments shutting down float tank centers from the lack of NSF certifications.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both years I&amp;#39;ve been the float conference have been amazing experiences.  I would recommend this conference for anyone who likes floating or the float culture.  I plan on going back next year August 20th-21st 2016 and would love to see more people out there! Every year it seems like more and more people attend and it&amp;#39;s really great to see the same people each year.  There is really something special about this industry that revolves around a sense of community and good will for others.  More info can be found on the float conference&amp;#39;s website  &lt;a href=&quot;http://floatconference.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 20:42:18 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/08/2015-8-16-Highlights_From_the_2015_Float_Conference</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/08/2015-8-16-Highlights_From_the_2015_Float_Conference</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why I Chose The Zen Float Tent</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After about a year and a half of consideration I&amp;#39;ve finally decided to purchase a Zen Float Tent.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://zenfloatco.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_zenfloattent.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of getting a float tank has been bouncing around in my mind for a couple of years now.  I had thought about the Escape Pod Tank or the Samadhi Tank but just couldn&amp;#39;t justify the cost of those for residential use.  These tanks are great, however paying $6,000+ for a tank just didn&amp;#39;t seem to be feasible for something that wouldn&amp;#39;t be used for commercial purposes.  The Zen Float Tent comes in just under $2,000 which is a lot more affordable especially considering that the cost of salt could run you close to $600 to fill it up initially (plus more for maintenance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three reasons why to choose the Zen Float Tent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Affordable&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Light weight&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Aesthetically Pleasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to purchase a higher end float tank for my home (or even a float center) the Escape Pod Tank is on the top of the list.  They are very durable (stainless steel) and the filtration system seems to be very robust.  Also their pricing is very reasonable at under $10,000 for a commercial grade tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what the Escape Pod looks like (2015 model).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://escapepodtank.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/ywoNiObl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically with a commercial grade tank they have higher end filters that clean the water much more quickly than in a residential tank.  In the case of my setup I will have another filtration system besides the standard one that comes with the Zen Float Tent.  The reason being is that I know many people who are interested in floating and want to make sure the water is very pure for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Custom filtration system:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible additional filter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Intex-1500-Gallon-Filter-Pump-120-Volt/dp/B005QIYM6E/ref=sr_1_1?srs=2594064011&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1431293710&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Intex+1500+Pool+filter+pump&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_filter.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this tank I plan on using 35% hydrogen peroxide to help sanitize the water. H202 + UV has been studied as an effective way to clean/disinfect the water. See the EPA post about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://iaspub.epa.gov/tdb/pages/treatment/treatmentOverview.do?treatmentProcessId=-300168699&quot;/&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; There also have been many studies done on the combination of UV + H202 in disinfecting water which can be found on&lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?start=10&amp;q=h202+and+uv+sanitizing+water&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0,26&quot;/&gt; Google Scholar.&lt;/a&gt;
If your really interested in how this works UV + H202 forms &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydroxyl_radical&quot;/&gt;hydroxyl radicals&lt;/a&gt;which are often referred to as the &amp;quot;detergents&amp;quot; of the atmosphere because they react with many pollutants, often acting as the first step to their removal.  This makes sense that UV + H202 can disinfect water effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically H202 comes in 3% solutions but for the sake of sanitization 35% makes more sense economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Certified-Hydrogen-Peroxide-Dropper-Bottle/dp/B00J0DAAVW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1436357494&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=hydrogen+peroxide+35&amp;pebp=1436357532762&amp;perid=1FWDJS2RPAWBGKVQR61H&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_h202b.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zen Float Tent comes with one filter pump which includes a UV light (note: the new upgraded tent v1.5 includes two pumps). Just to make sure that the water is ultra pure I may end up getting another UV light to attach to the intex pool pump just to have more of those hydroxyl radicals that I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Pondmaster-02910-Violet-Clarifier-10watt/dp/B00025YVGW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1436358117&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=ultraviolet+light+pond
&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/rsz_uvlight.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Isolating sound&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound isolation is a typical problem with float tanks especially low frequency sounds such as people walking or cars driving by.  These sounds can travel well throughs solid objects such as the walls and the water that you will be floating in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this issue I plan on purchasing a neoprene rubber anti-vibration pad to help absorb these sounds if they are too distracting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Shop-Fox-W1322-Anti-Vibration-24-Inch/dp/B000OQTV2I/ref=sr_1_1/191-8040367-2256009?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1431379730&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=neoprene+sheet&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/vibrationPad.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally there is the issue of the tank leaking if some sharp object gets into the tank and tears the vinyl.  For this I plan on purchasing an industrial spill berm to catch water if the tent leaks.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aireindustrial.net/spill-berms/spill-containment-berm.asp&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tank/spillberm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/07/Why_I_Chose_The_Zen_Float_Tent</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/07/Why_I_Chose_The_Zen_Float_Tent</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>3 Parts of An Automated Float Tank Center</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The reason for this post is to speak in more detail about what will be required to create a fully automated float center. Some of the components that will need to be implemented will include Arduinos(microcontrollers), access cards(to get into building), a database(storing user info), Stripe/Paypal(credit card processor), and networking to tie the whole system into the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Various components to the system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will break down the whole system into 3 different systems. These systems are:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scheduling/Billing System&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Building security&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Filtration/clean up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Scheduling/Billing System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the system that will be designed around a website that will allow floaters to sign up on the website and schedule floats.&lt;br&gt;
There are already many versions of this type of software developed however one needs to be custom designed to fit in with the automated float center. Some examples include:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://floathelm.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;FloatHelm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frontdeskhq.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;FrontDesk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zenplanner.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;ZenPlanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindbodyonline.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;MindBodyOnline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Scheduling all starts with the customer wanting to book at float online.  He will go to the website and there will be a button that will pull up the scheduling application.  From there they can pick the time they want to float and then pay using a credit card.  This system will need to be tied into the building security system which will permit the user to gain access using their access card or PIN number when they show up to float.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process might look like this:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;User books/pays for float online&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Access card is activated for the time they have scheduled&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They show up and their access card allows them to enter their specified float room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Building security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain security for the building and the customers who use this facility there must be strict access into the building only permitted if that user has scheduled a float.
The reason for strict access is that we only want floaters who are permitted into the facility at their designated float time,  if this is not the case then people may be tempted to steal floats or to disrupt the peaceful waiting room which could become overcrowded.  The access control software would be able to keep track of how long users stay at the float tank center including time during, before, and after their float.  These metrics would be a lot easier to obtain if the only permitted people into the building have been authorized to float.  These metrics could be used to help cut back on unnecessary time spent between float sessions and to help provide an overall better experience for the floater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This aspect of the float center would operate similar to a 24/7 tanning salon except that users only have a certain time window in which they can gain access to the facility.  This system would need an access card reader or PIN pad on the front door and on each of the float tank room doors.  When the user arrives they will already know which room they are floating in via text message or email, so they can go into the facility and head to the room they have booked for floating.  Once the user enters their room they will take a shower and then enter the tank.  A sensor will be placed on the door of the room which will detect when it was opened and will know to start a timer which will play music in the tank when the float time is up.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain problems can appear at this stage of the process:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What if the floater arrives late for their float?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;How do you prevent a floater from staying longer in the tank?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What if the floater has health complications in the tank?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat some of these problems there will need to be fail-safes in place.  Let&amp;#39;s take the example of the floater arriving late for their appointment.  If the floater arrives more than 15 minutes late the front door would not allow them to enter.  This would keep the process moving smoothly because if a floater arrives late it could push back the floats for other people.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that a floater stays in the tank longer than scheduled, there will be various ways to &amp;quot;encourage&amp;quot; them to get out of the tank. When the time is up there first might be some music that begins to play in their float tank.  Then if they still have not gotten out (motion sensor to detect this) a light could come on and then start flashing if they continue to stay in the tank.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third problem is a bit tricky because without someone being on site it might be hard to know if someone is having problems in the tank.  This issue could be compared to a swimming pool that has no lifeguard on duty where there would be a disclaimer that in the event something bad happens there may be no one to help you.  Besides this disclaimer another useful option would be to place an &amp;quot;emergency&amp;quot; button inside the tank so if the floater is having issues they can hit the button and it will dial 911 and they could talk to them via a speaker in the tank.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Filtration/clean up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between float sessions it is necessary to run the tank&amp;#39;s filtration system in order to clean all of the water of bad bacteria and pathogens that may have accumulated after a person&amp;#39;s float.  This system will be implemented by using a motion detector to sense when a person has gotten out of the tank and has started their post float shower.  Something to keep in mind the system would have to verify that that floater&amp;#39;s time has been used up in the event that they were planning on going back to continue floating.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically the floater will use a towel, ear plugs, and maybe Q-tips which they will need to dispose of after their float is over.  For this type of float center there would be a trash can and a laundry basket in order to keep the room clean.  Also it is critical that there is a large stack of towels laid out so that the every floater will have fresh towels throughout the day.  At the end of the day there will need to be a person who comes in an does laundry and takes out the trash.  There could be an incentive where a floater gets one float at half price if they do some chores around the center and help clean up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum things up there are a lot of technical aspects that go into creating an automated float tank center.  Clearly this system needs to be well thought out ahead of time and designed carefully with fail-safes in place to help deal with any problems that might occur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/03/How_To_Design_An_Automated_Float_Tank_Center%20copy</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/03/How_To_Design_An_Automated_Float_Tank_Center%20copy</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Automated Float Tank Center</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;First off, you are probably wondering what I mean by a fully automated float tank center.  Let&amp;#39;s start by looking at what a typical flotation center looks like.  If you are unfamiliar with a float tank center imagine a tanning salon but instead of tanning beds there are float tanks in each room. If you are curious about what a float tank looks like check out the blog post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.floatgeek.com/2014/12/Intro/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Most of the float centers I&amp;#39;ve been to consist of a front desk where a person will help sign you in and will explain the process of how to use the tank.  The process would go something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Walk into float center (usually after having made an appointment)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Talk to the person at the front desk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Typically they will explain how the process works (which might include taking a shower before/after, using ear plugs, and not getting water in your eye)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enter the room you are going to float in&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Then you shower/float/shower (the person will knock on the tank or you will hear music when float is over)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You pay the person at the front desk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;After you&#39;ve paid, you can relax in the waiting room or leave and enjoy the post float glow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a fully automated float center could substantially cut back on the overhead expenses of paying a person to run the front desk.  The process would essentially be the same, except for speaking with a person you would go to the room you booked online.  Keep in mind, this system is designed for people who have experience floating so they won&amp;#39;t need someone to explain details.  This process might go something like this:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Book a float online and pay with a credit card&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Visit the float center with an access card or a 4 digit PIN that will allow you to get into the building&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You can use the same access card/PIN to access the float room you booked&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Then you shower/float/shower (music will play in your tank when the time is up)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;After the float your free to leave and enjoy the post float glow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the major difference between these two types of float tank centers is that one has a person present during floats.  Having an automated float center eliminates this extra cost which results in giving the customer access to cheaper floats.  For this automated float tank center I believe the best pricing model would be subscription based. I could see this being extremely useful for a floating cooperative business so that after each person floats they might add a bit more salt into the tank, wipe the tank down, and put their dirty towel into a laundry basket. This could be a very sustainable business since a majority of the cost for running a float tank center comes from paying a staff to be there to check people in.  Something to keep in mind is that this is a very high level overview of what I see in my ideal float center.  In future posts I will break it down into exactly how the system will be setup.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/02/Automated_Float_Tank_Center</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/02/Automated_Float_Tank_Center</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Companies That Deserve Your Money</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coach.me&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/coachme.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Coach.me is a website and mobile application that helps you reach your goals.  The idea is you can sign up for various goals such as (no alcohol, no cigarettes, meditation, etc.) and you can keep track of the days you complete your habit.  This is such a powerful tool that can really help you achieve whatever you are trying to accomplish.  I highly recommend this and have been using it since November 2012.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rdio.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/rdio-logo-300x132.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Rdio is a service that allows you to stream music for only $10 a month or $5 a month if you are a student.  The advantage of using this service compared to paying individually for songs would be that you have unlimited access to music.  Also, if you listen to over 10 new songs a month it easily could be worth it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://chipotle.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/chipotle_logo_horizontal_inv.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Chipotle is not your typical Mexican restaurant.  They have a very different atmosphere than a typical restaurant.  Chipotle is very particular about where their ingredients are sourced, and look for sustainable options and naturally fed meat.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://simple.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/simple-bank-branding-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Simple is a bank that truly puts their customers first.  They have a built in budgeting system that can facilitate saving up for any type of purchase.  The bank is also known for having lower fees than a typical bank.  Simple is a bank you can be proud of!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/duckduckgo-logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If your tired of worrying about who is snooping on your search engine queries look no further.  DuckDuckGo.com is a great website which doesn&amp;#39;t track or retain information about what you search for.  Now, one might not care about allowing others to view what data they look at but the main issue here is that bigger search engines put you in a filter bubble.  Here is a great TED talk about filter bubbles that explains how certain search engines will give you bias results based on your past history.  This may seem like a good thing, but in reality it is not giving you an accurate picture of the world, but that confirms your own beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;auto-resizable-iframe&quot;&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;iframe
           frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
           allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;
           src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B8ofWFx525s&quot;&gt;
       &lt;/iframe&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://betterment.com/invite/connorknabe&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;/images/logos/betterment_283_224_v2_0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Betterment is a great tool for investors that don&amp;#39;t want to pay high fees for getting involved in the mutual fund industry.  They use low cost index funds and bonds that allow them to charge incredibly low fees.  They charge between .15% and .35% depending on how much money you have invested with them.  I highly recommend this service and use it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/02/Companies_That_Deserve_Your_Money</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/02/Companies_That_Deserve_Your_Money</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>5 Reasons why you should float</title>
				<description>&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;The float tank can help us reflect on life.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    We are constantly connected to our computers, smartphones, and televisions throughout the day. How often do we have to be with ourselves to reflect on life?
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Allows you to approach problems from a different perspective.[1]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    Because the tank environment is unlike any other experience on earth, it provides a great opportunity to totally focus on a problem at hand without distractions.  
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can learn things faster in the tank.[2]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        As talked about in the &lt;i&gt;The Book of Floating&lt;/i&gt; by Michael Hutchison there is a phenomena known as superlearning, which allows you to learn things faster than outside of the tank.
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Float tanks can allow you to achieve a sense of well being[3]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        There have been studies that show float tanks can help you live a happier life.  This is probably due to the fact that you are spending time with yourself and this can allow you to deal with problems that may be bothering you.
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Can reduce the hormone cortisol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        Why is this beneficial? Well, cortisol is known as a stress hormone which is released in response to stress.  If you can lower this hormone it may help you feel less stressed and more relaxed.
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
[1]&amp;quot;The Effects of REST and Hemispheric Synchronization Compared to the Effects of REST and Guided Imagery on the Enhancement of Creativity in Problem-Solving&amp;quot; -  Baker D.A
&lt;br&gt;
[2]&amp;quot;The effects of flotation restricted environmental stimulation therapy on learning: subjective evaluation and EEG measurements&amp;quot; - Taylor, T.
&lt;br&gt;
[3]&amp;quot;Case studies on fibromyalgia and burn-out depression using psychotherapy in combination with flotation-REST: Personality development and increased well-being.&amp;quot; - Åsenlöf, K., Olsson, S., Bood, S. Å., &amp;amp; Norlander, T.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2015/01/5_Reasons_To_Float</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2015/01/5_Reasons_To_Float</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Short Intro To This Blog</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;floating&quot;&gt;Floating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is going to be about floating and software development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Floating is the act of using a sensory deprivation/isolation tank in order to remove yourself from all of your senses.
The tank can be used to help people recover from workouts, relax, help with PTSD, addictions, and other mental illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are various types of tanks, some of which are small and look like a bathtub with a roof over them, while others are larger, open and fill the size of a room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The float tank is filled with around 800-1,000 lbs of Epsom salt which allows the user to float without any effort.  The density of the water is greater than the dead sea which can allow you to completely relax when lying in it.  The temperature of the water is also heated to the same temperature of the skin so you cannot feel where the water ends and the air begins.  Also, there is no light and ideally no sound.  Being deprived of all of your senses can put your body into an extremely relaxed state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a float tank looks like:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/floating/Sensory-Deprivation-Chamber-Would-You-Get-Into-One.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SensoryDeprivation&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open tank, especially useful for people with claustrophobia&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/floating/Open-Float-Tank-Neil-04-noglare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OpenFloat&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some look futuristic&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/floating/float-tank-spa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FloatSpa&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others are big enough to stand up in&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/floating/float-rooms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FloatRoom&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another futuristic tank&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/floating/float-isopod-floatation-tank-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FloatSpa&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;quot;software development&amp;quot; has a lot of misconceptions associated with it.  People may hear this term and think about a nerdy kid in his mom&amp;#39;s basement programming a website.  Others may think of a scene from &lt;i&gt;The Social Network&lt;/i&gt; when they were having a &amp;quot;Hackathon&amp;quot;.  When I tell people that I am a developer many of people will give me an &amp;quot;ooh/ahh&amp;quot; and explain how they have no idea how to code.  With this blog I would like to help debunk the myth that coding is hard.  If you know basic math and logic you can program.  It just takes time to learn these basic concepts, but anyone can do it.  Development teaches you how to problem solve and to approach problems from a different perspective.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quotes:&quot;&gt;Quotes:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Everybody in this country should learn how to program a computer... because it teaches you how to think.&amp;quot; - Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Talk is cheap. Show me the code.” ― Linus Torvalds&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://floatgeek.com/2014/12/Intro</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://floatgeek.com/2014/12/Intro</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
